Time heals the heart. Faith heals the rest.
Diary of a Mad Black Woman is a drama, romance,
comedy film directed by Darren Grant.
Charles, an attorney, and Helen, his devoted wife, seem to have
everything – money, a beautiful mansion – the American Dream.
However, as Helen prepares to celebrate their 18th wedding anniversary, her life takes an unexpected twist
when she comes home to find her clothes packed up in a U-Haul van parked in the driveway.
Charles is divorcing her and kicks her out.
Helen moves in with her grandmother Madea, an old woman
who doesn't take any lip from anyone.
Madea helps Helen through these tough times by showing
her what is really important in life.
Helen is forced to rediscover love, life, and
religion in her pursuit for happiness.
Helen McCarter, played by Kimberly Elise.
Charles McCarter, played by Steve Harris.
Madea / Brian / Joe, played by Tyler Perry.
Orlando, played by Shemar Moore.
Brenda, played by Lisa Marcos.
Debrah, played by Tamara Taylor.
Diary of a Mad Black Woman is a 2005 American romantic comedy drama
film directed by Darren Grant and written by Tyler Perry.
Inspired by the play of the same name, it marks Perry's feature film
debut and is the first entry in the Madea film franchise.
Starring Perry alongside Kimberly Elise, Steve Harris, Shemar Moore, and Cicely Tyson, it tells the story of a woman who is thrown out of her house by her
husband on their 18th wedding anniversary and subsequently moves in with her grandmother, and is the only film written, but not directed, by Perry.
Filmed in Atlanta and Fairburn, Georgia, and released theatrically by Lionsgate Films
on February 25, 2005, the film grossed $50.6 million in North America.
The sequel, Madea's Family Reunion, was released on February 24, 2006.
The film explores themes of new love, faith,
forgiveness, crooked lawyer, revenge.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and mind_bending.